<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>jManage - Web and Command Line Based JMX Client</title>
  </header>
  <body>
    <section>
      <title>News !</title>
      <p>
          - <strong>Aug 10, 2005</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;
          <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=111374&amp;package_id=120380&amp;release_id=348348">
              jManage 0.5.4</a> is now available.
          This release contains some of the <a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?func=browse&amp;group_id=111374&amp;atid=659060">feature requests</a>.
          <br/>
          See <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/shownotes.php?release_id=348348">Release Notes</a> for more information.
          <br/><br/>
          - <strong>Jul 31, 2005</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;jManage 0.5.3 is now available.
          Along with some bug fixes, this release adds JMXMP support.
          It can be downloaded
          <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=111374&amp;package_id=120380&amp;release_id=346021">here</a>.
          <br/><br/>
          - <strong>Jun 22, 2005</strong> jManage 0.5.2 is now available. It can be downloaded
            <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=111374&amp;package_id=120380&amp;release_id=336967">here</a>.
          <br/><br/>
          - <strong>Jun 03, 2005</strong> Do you use CruiseControl? Manage it with jManage 0.5.
            <a href="http://www.coffeebreaks.org/blogs/?p=7">See how</a>.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>jManage Overview</title>
      <p>
jManage is a open source, web and command-line based JMX client, which provides a
centralized console for managing application clusters and distributed-application
production environments.
<br/><br/>
Following is a screenshot of jManage 0.5 version:
<br/><br/>
    <a href="/images/screenshots/clusterMBeanView.gif">
        <img src="/images/screenshots/clusterMBeanView.gif" alt="Screenshot" width="300" height="150"/></a>
<br/><br/>
    <a href="/screenshots.html">See More Screenshots</a>
<br/><br/>
          jManage 0.5 is available for download on the
          <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=111374&amp;package_id=120380">
              downloads</a> page. This release has the following features:
<br/><br/>
    - Web based interface, which allows jManage to be used from behind firewall.
<br/>
    - Production level security.
<br/>
    - Command line interface - Useful for scripting and automation.
<br/>
    - Application Cluster Support - Change attribute values
      and perform operations across the cluster.
<br/>
    - Authentication and fine-grained Authorization - Control what operations
      and attributes are accessible.
<br/>
    - Support for different J2EE app servers.
<br/><br/>
          jManage is being built keeping security in mind, as the main target
          usage of jManage is in the production environment. Production
          environments usually have limited access and are managed by an
          operations team. jManage lets the operations team monitor the
          production environment (via browser or command line) and also
          allows the operations team to give controlled access to developers, QA
          and others. Operations team can create jManage users and assign
          roles to these users. Access to different features can be controlled
          by assigining permissions to various roles. Permission can be granted
          even at the level of MBean attributes or operations.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>jManage Platform</title>
        <p>
            jManage is a <a href="http://struts.apache.org/">Struts</a> and
            <a href="http://jetty.mortbay.org/">Jetty</a> based web application,
            which provides both web and command line interface to manage JMX enabled
            applications. jManage 0.5 version supports
            the following servers:
        <br/><br/>
            - JBoss
        <br/>
            - JMX Remoting (JSR 160)
        <br/>
            - Bea Weblogic
        <br/>
            - IBM WebSphere
        <br/><br/>
            jManage command line interface uses java serialization over HTTP
            to connect to the jManage web application. This allows the command
            line client to talk to the jmanage server across the firewall.
        </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Typical Deployment</title>
      <p>
          jManage is typically deployed in a production environment in the
          same network as the applications to be managed. This allows jManage
          to access the JMX enabled applications via any JMX remoting protocol
          supported by that application. Users access jManage over HTTP via
          a web browser or command line.
          <br/><br/>
          <img src="/images/jManage-deploy.jpg" alt="Typical jManage Deployment"/>
          <br/><br/>
          Access to jManage is controlled via username/password provided
          by the System Administrators or the Operations team. Admins can
          control access even at the MBean attribute or operation level.
          <br/><br/>
          User activites are logged in a log file, which can be audited
          by the System Administrators.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
