<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>jManage - Web and Command Line Based JMX Client</title>
  </header>
  <body>
    <section>
      <title>News !</title>
      <p>
          New to jManage? Read the introductory article at <a href="http://www.javaworld.com/javaworld/jw-01-2006/jw-0116-jmanage.html">JavaWorld</a>.
          <br/><br/>
          For the latest on jManage, please see the <a href="http://jmanage.blogspot.com">jManage Blog</a>.
          <br/><br/>
          jManage 1.0 builds are available for download
          <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=111374&amp;package_id=166109">here</a>.
          <br/><br/>
          <a href="/newsArchive.html">News Archive >></a>
      </p>

    </section>
    <section>
      <title>jManage Overview</title>
      <p>
jManage is a open source, web and command-line based JMX client, which provides a
centralized console for managing application clusters and distributed-application
environments. jManage goes beyond an ordinary JMX client by providing features
like Alerts, Graphs, Security, SNMP support, etc. The jManage mission is to
provide an open source management platform, which can be used to manage
and monitor complete production environment.
<br/><br/>
jManage is successfully being used by
various users, in Development, QA, Staging and Production environments.
It is very easy to setup jManage. Download
<a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=111374&amp;package_id=166109">now</a>
and get started.
<br/><br/>
Following is a screenshot of jManage web interface:
<br/><br/>
    <a href="/images/screenshots/clusterMBeanView.gif">
        <img src="/images/screenshots/clusterMBeanView.gif" alt="Screenshot" width="300" height="150"/></a>
<br/><br/>
    You can see more screenshots <a href="/screenshots.html">here</a>.
      </p>

    </section>
    <section>
      <title>jManage Features</title>
      <p>
          jManage 1.0 has the following features:
<br/><br/>
    - Web based interface, which allows jManage to be used from behind firewall.
<br/>
    - Production level security.
<br/>
    - Command line interface - Useful for scripting and automation.
<br/>
    - Application Cluster Support - Change attribute values
      and perform operations across the cluster.
<br/>
    - Authentication and fine-grained Authorization to control which MBean
      operations and attributes are accessible.
<br/>
    - Support for different J2EE app servers and JDK1.5.
<br/>
    - Runtime Graphs.
<br/>
    - MBean attribute value monitoring.
<br/>
    - Alerts based on MBean notifications and MBean attribute monitors.
<br/>
    - Support for Open MBean types: CompositeData and TabularData
<br/>
    - Basic SNMP support
<br/>
    - Framework to define custom DataFormat classes for custom objects.
<br/>
     - Support for external login modules (JAAS based with name and password callback)
<br/><br/>
          jManage is being built keeping security in mind, as one of the
          usages of jManage is in the production environment. Production
          environments usually have limited access and are managed by an
          operations team. jManage lets the operations team monitor the
          production environment (via browser or command line) and also
          allows the operations team to give controlled access to developers, QA
          and others. Operations team can create jManage users and assign
          roles to these users. Access to different features can be controlled
          by assigining permissions to various roles. Permission can be granted
          even at the level of MBean attributes or operations.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>jManage Platform</title>
        <p>
            jManage is a <a href="http://struts.apache.org/">Struts</a> and
            <a href="http://jetty.mortbay.org/">Jetty</a> based web application,
            which provides both web and command line interface to manage JMX enabled
            applications. jManage 1.0 version supports
            the following:
        <br/><br/>
            - JBoss
        <br/>
            - Bea Weblogic
        <br/>
            - IBM WebSphere
        <br/>
            - JDK1.5
        <br/>
            - MX4J
        <br/>
            - JMX Remoting (JSR 160)
        <br/><br/>
            jManage command line interface uses java serialization over HTTP
            to connect to the jManage web application. This allows the command
            line client to connect to the jmanage server across the firewall.
        </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Typical Deployment</title>
      <p>
          jManage is typically deployed in a production environment in the
          same network as the applications to be managed. This allows jManage
          to access the JMX enabled applications via any JMX remoting protocol
          supported by that application. Users access jManage over HTTP via
          a web browser or command line.
          <br/><br/>
          <img src="/images/jManage-deploy.gif" alt="Typical jManage Deployment"/>
          <br/><br/>
          Access to jManage is controlled via username/password provided
          by the System Administrators or the Operations team. Admins can
          control access even at the MBean attribute or operation level.
          <br/><br/>
          User activites are logged in a log file, which can be audited
          by the System Administrators.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
