<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>jManage User Quotes</title>
  </header>
  <body>
	<p style="font-size: 10px;">
      "I've been trying out various jManage releases for quite some time and have to say that the jManage project has been extremely responsive to bug reports, suggestions, and feedback in general.
	   jManage fills an important niche in that there was no freely available general JMX HTML console before this point. [Yes, I know about JBoss' console, but last I knew you couldn't just install it and point to any JVM with an active JSR 160 connector. Sun has a JMX HTML console, but it's wrapped up in a commercial offering.]"
	   <br/>- <i>Jess Hole, PTC</i>
    </p><br/>
	<p style="font-size: 10px;">
	  "Nice tool. Easy to use, secured, two-left-hand-enabled :)
	  Thanks guys." <br/>- <i>Cram</i>  
    </p><br/>
    <p style="font-size: 10px;">
	  "Great Job! I love where you are taking jManage. It is my team's primary tool when troubleshooting at remote customer sites.
	  Thanks for all the effort and this truly great and simple to use product! IMO - no other product compares to jManage - now with dashboards - 
	  we can offer specialized views geared towards our system to further reduce turnaround time in the field." <br/>- <i>Jody Brownell </i>
	</p><br/>
    <p style="font-size: 10px;">	
	"The tool is quite nice. The screenshots on the site don't do it justice, and I've been hesitant to look at it somewhat
	because the screenshots made it look pretty basic. But when I did look, I was amazed to see how much is there."
    <br/>- <i>Joe Mocker</i>  
    </p><br/>
    <p style="font-size: 10px;">	    
    "Good luck with jManage. jManage is a great idea, and the product has
    already served us for some time, allowing us to avoid e.g. MC4J Console 
    on lots of project member's PC's or, even worse, web front-end on each MBeanServer 
    on our installations."
    <br/>- <i>Kyrre Lugg, Project Engineer - Software, Tomra Systems ASA</i>  
    </p><br/>
  </body>
</document>
