<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>jManage Command Line Reference</title>
  </header>
  <body>
    <section>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <p>
      jManage command line interface (CLI) supports most of the commonly used JMX
      operations. It uses jManage server as the proxy for communicating with
      the JMX enabled applications.
      <br/>
      [If time permits we will release a standalone command line interface as
      part of 0.5 release, which could be used to directly interact with the JMX
      enabled applications. If not, this will follow immediatly after 0.5 release.]
      <br/><br/>
      jManage CLI is invoked by running jmanage script (jmanage.cmd for windows
      and jmanage.sh for unix):
      <br/><br/>
      jmanage [-username &lt;username&gt;] [-password &lt;password&gt;] [-verbose[=&lt;level&gt;]] [command] [command args]
      <br/><br/>
      The username/password are for authenticating with the jManage server.
      Users in jManage are created by System Administrator via the web
      UI.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Usages</title>
        <p>
        jManage CLI can be be used in command execution mode or prompt mode.
        In the command execution mode, the command is specified as an argument
        to the jmanage script. For example:
        <br/><br/>
        jmanage -username admin -password 123456 execute myApplication/myMBean myOperation arg1
        <br/><br/>
        In this mode, jmanage CLI executes the command and exits.
        <br/><br/>
        If command is not specified as an argument to the jmanage script, after
        successful authentication, you get into a prompt mode. The commands
        can then be executed in the prompt mode.
        </p>
    </section>
    <section>
       <title>Commands</title>
       <table>
          <tr>
            <td>apps</td>
            <td>Lists all configured applications in jManage.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
           <td>mbeans</td>
           <td>Queries mbeans for the given application.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>cmbeans</td>
            <td>Lists configured mbeans for the given application.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>info</td>
            <td>Display information about the mbean.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>get</td>
            <td>Gets attribute values for given mbean.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>print</td>
            <td>Prints tab delimited value(s) for given mbean attribute(s).</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>set</td>
            <td>Sets attribute value. Used for setting complex values (e.g. with spaces).</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>setattrs</td>
            <td>Sets one or more attribute values.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>execute</td>
            <td>Executes given operation on mbean.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>help</td>
            <td>Prints jManage command line help. help &lt;command&gt; provides detailed help on given command.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>exit</td>
            <td>Exits from jManage command prompt mode.</td>
          </tr>
       </table>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
