<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Security in jManage</title>
  </header>
  <body>
    <section>
      <title>The "admin" user</title>
      <p>
        jManage requires a "admin" user to be setup during installation. The
        password of this user is used to encrypt a "symmetric" key which is
        generated during insallation. The encrypted key is stored in jmanage-key
        file under "config" directory. This scheme avoids writing the key to the
        disk in its clear form. For this reason, the password of this "admin"
        user is required when starting jManage application.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Username/Password based access</title>
      <p>
        The only way jManage applications can be accessed is via username and
        password. The application only allows 3 invalid attempts before locking
        the account. Once the account has been locked, someone who has access to
        User management (normaly from operations/admin team), needs to
        unlock the account, before this username can be used again.
        <br/><br/>
        The number of invalid attempts can be configured in
        jmanage.properties (default is 3).
        <br/><br/>
        jManage users are defined in jmanage-users.xml file under the config
        directory. This file is managed using the User Management functionalty
        in jManage Web interface. The passwords are stored as a one-way hash in
        this file. jManage by default uses SHA-1 algorithm, but this can be
        changed in jmanage.properties during initial setup. jManage has also been
        tested with SHA-256.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>User Roles</title>
      <p>
      A User can belong to one or more roles (at this time the UI supports only
      one role per user). The user roles are defined in jmanage-user-roles.xml.
      By default jManage comes with two pre-defined roles: Administrator and User;
      Administrator has complete access whereas User has read-only access.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>ACL</title>
      <p>
      The access is controlled by defininig ACEs (Access Control Entities) in
      acl-config.properties file. The permissions can be configured either at
      the user level or at the role level.
      <br/><br/>
      jManage also provides a mechanism to specify ACEs at the MBean attribute
      or operation level. Please see
      <a href="accessControl.html">Access Control</a>
      for more info.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Application Passwords</title>
      <p>
      The application server passwords are encrypted using the key generated
      during jManage setup. jManage uses a 128 bit TripleDES key which is ecrypted
      with the Password Based Encryption (PBE) using the "admin" user password.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>SSL</title>
      <p>
      By default jManage works over http. SSL can be enabled by uncommenting
      the following properties in jmanage.properties:
      <br/><br/>
      jmanage.ssl.port=9091
      <br/>
      jmanage.ssl.keyfilename=keystore
      <br/>
      jmanage.ssl.password=password
      <br/>
      jmanage.ssl.keypassword=password
      <br/><br/>
      When SSL is enabled, jManage only listens on SSL port, and HTTP access is
      disabled.
      <br/><br/>
      Note that the "jmanage.url" property also needs to be updated for the
      command line interface to work.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>