<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Getting Involved</title>
  </header>
  <body>
      <section>
        <title>Setup the Development environment</title>
        <p>
            Please follow the <a href="http://www.jmanage.org/wiki/index.php/JManage_Build_Guide">Bulid Guide</a>
            to setup your development environment. Please connect to CVS
            as "anonymous" user and check-out the "jmanage" module.
            <br/>
        </p>
      </section>
      <section>
          <title>Join the project</title>
          <ul>
              <li>
                If you have not setup a SourceForge account, please do it
                <a href="http://sourceforge.net/account/newuser_emailverify.php">here</a>.
              </li>
              <li>
                Take a look at Open and Unassigned feature requests
                  <a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?atid=659060&amp;group_id=111374&amp;func=browse">
                      here</a>.
                  Please go through them and pick up the one that interests you.
              </li>
              <li>
                Send an email to team@jmanage.org
                with your SourceForge username and the feature request that you are
                interested in. Please also indicate the expected completion time
                for the feature request, to help with the release planning.
              </li>
              <li>
                We will add you to the project and we will assign the feature
                request to you.
              </li>
              <li>
                Please join the jmanage-team mailing list
                <a href="http://sourceforge.net/mail/?group_id=111374">here</a>.
                You will be able to do this, only after you have been added
                to the project.
              </li>
              <li>
                After implementing the feature request, please submit the
                code changes to team@jmanage.org. The code changes will be reviewed
                and then applied to the CVS.
              </li>
              <li>
                After your first feature request has been incorporated
                and you are interested in continuing,
                we will provide you with the CVS access, so that
                you can directly check-in your changes into CVS.
              </li>
          </ul>
      </section>
      <section>
          <title>Miscellaneous</title>
          <ul>
              <li>
                  Please add the following text at the top of each new file
                  that you add: <br/><br/>
                    /** <br/>
                     * Copyright (c) 2004-2005 jManage.org<br/>
                     * <br/><br/>
                     * This is a free software; you can redistribute it and/or<br/>
                     * modify it under the terms of the license at<br/>
                     * http://www.jmanage.org.<br/>
                     * <br/><br/>
                     * Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software<br/>
                     * distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,<br/>
                     * WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.<br/>
                     * See the License for the specific language governing permissions and<br/>
                     * limitations under the License.<br/>
                     */
              </li>
              <li>
                  Specify your name against the @author tag.
              </li>
              <li>
                  Please follow the Java coding standards. We will soon
                  add appropriate tools to do these checks.
              </li>
              <li>
                  Please make sure that your code is within 80 characters column
                  width.
              </li>
              <li>
                For any design discussions, please use the Developers forum
                <a href="http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=381566">
                here</a>.
              </li>
              <li>
                We use <a href="http://www.skype.com">Skype</a> for instant
                messaging among the team. Please send your Skype user Id to
                team@jmanage.org.
              </li>
          </ul>
       </section>
  </body>
</document>