<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>jManage Features</title>
    <authors>
        <person name="Avneet Singh" email="asingh@jmanage.org"/>
    </authors>
  </header>
  <body>

      <p>
		<br/>
		<strong>jManage 1.5 beta has the following features:</strong>
		<br/><br/>
		    - Easy to use Web based interface, which allows jManage to be used from behind firewall.
		<br/><br/>
			- Dashboard framework to build custom dashboards. Customized dashboards can be tailored to specific objectives. These dashboards are,<br/>
				a. Live -> automatically refreshed to provide latest information.<br/>
				b. Customized -> users can build a dashboard from scratch or customize an existing one to suit their needs.
		<br/><br/>
			- Connector framework for monitoring/managing non-JMX based environments. 
			This framework can be used to expose necessary information on a non-JMX based environment as an application of MBeans. 
			These applications can be registered, monitored and managed through jManage.
		<br/><br/>
		    - MBean Info layering framework to provide additional information for MBeans. JDK 1.5 MBeans now get presented with MBean, attribute and operation descriptions
		<br/><br/>
		    - Production level security.
		<br/><br/>
		    - Command line interface - Useful for scripting and automation.
		<br/><br/>
		    - Application Cluster Support - Change attribute values
		      and perform operations across the cluster.
		<br/><br/>
			- Authentication and fine-grained Authorization to control access to different MBean 
			  attributes and operations.
		<br/><br/>
		    - Support for various J2EE app servers, JDK1.5 and other JSR160 enabled applications.
		<br/><br/>
		    - Custom Graphs.
		<br/><br/>
		    - MBean attribute value monitoring.
		<br/><br/>
		    - Email and console alerts based on MBean notifications and MBean attribute monitors.
		<br/><br/>
		    - Support for Open MBean types: CompositeData and TabularData
		<br/><br/>
		    - Basic SNMP support (SNMP 1.0)
		<br/><br/>
		    - Framework to define custom DataFormat classes for custom objects.
		<br/><br/>
		     - Support for external login modules (JAAS based with name and password callback)
		<br/><br/>
		     - jManage can be accessed via Java APIs, which allows jManage to be used as a backend 
		     system and also allows applications to register themselves as they come online.
		<br/><br/>
		          jManage is being built keeping security in mind, as one of the
		          usages of jManage is in the production environment. Production
		          environments usually have limited access and are managed by an
		          operations team. jManage lets the operations team monitor the
		          production environment (via browser or command line) and also
		          allows the operations team to give controlled access to developers, QA
		          and others. Operations team can create jManage users and assign
		          roles to these users. Access to different features can be controlled
		          by assigining permissions to various roles. Permission can be granted
		          even at the level of MBean attributes or operations.
		<br/><br/>
      </p>

  </body>
</document>
